(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T21:17:07.140015",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
探していたんだ キミの笑顔
I was looking for your smile,
ずっと前から 恋してた
I've been in love with you for so long.
ドキドキしちゃう この気持ち
My heart throbs with these feelings,
キミに届いて 欲しいんだ
I want them to reach you.
朝の光が 差し込む部屋で
In a room filled with morning light,
今日もキミのこと 考えてる
I'm thinking of you again today.
いつも通りの 街の景色が
The familiar scenery of the town...
キミがいるだけで 特別になる
becomes special just by having you in it.
すれ違うたび 高鳴る胸
Every time we pass each other, my heart races.
目と目が合えば 照れちゃうけど
When our eyes meet, I feel shy, but...
ほんとの気持ち 伝えたいな
I want to tell you my true feelings,
この手をぎゅっと 握りしめて
holding this hand tightly.
探していたんだ キミの笑顔
I was looking for your smile,
ずっと前から 恋してた
I've been in love with you for so long.
ドキドキしちゃう この気持ち
My heart throbs with these feelings,
キミに届いて 欲しいんだ
I want them to reach you.
どんな未来が 待っていても
No matter what future awaits,
キミと一緒に 歩きたい
I want to walk together with you.
溢れる想い 抱きしめて
Embracing these overflowing feelings,
走り出そう よーいドン！
let's start running, ready set go!
うまくいかない 日もあるけれど
Even though there are days when things don't go well,
キミの一言で 元気になる
just a single word from you cheers me up.
不思議な魔法に かかったみたい
It's like I'm under a strange magic spell,
世界がキラキラ 輝きだす
the world begins to sparkle brightly.
つまずいたって 諦めない
Even if I stumble, I won't give up.
キミの隣で 笑っていたい
I want to keep smiling by your side.
特別な日々 重ねながら
As we layer these special days together,
どこまでも行こう 一緒にね
let's go anywhere together!
探していたんだ キミの笑顔
I was looking for your smile,
ずっと前から 恋してた
I've been in love with you for so long.
ドキドキしちゃう この気持ち
My heart throbs with these feelings,
キミに届いて 欲しいんだ
I want them to reach you.
どんな未来が 待っていても
No matter what future awaits,
キミと一緒に 歩きたい
I want to walk together with you.
溢れる想い 抱きしめて
Embracing these overflowing feelings,
走り出そう よーいドン！
let's start running, ready set go!
探していたんだ キミの笑顔
I was looking for your smile,
ずっと前から 恋してた
I've been in love with you for so long.
ドキドキしちゃう この気持ち
My heart throbs with these feelings,
キミに届いて 欲しいんだ
I want them to reach you.
どんな未来が 待っていても
No matter what future awaits,
キミと一緒に 歩きたい
I want to walk together with you.
溢れる想い 抱きしめて
Embracing these overflowing feelings,
走り出そう よーいドン！
let's start running, ready set go!
ずっとずっと 大好きだよ
I love you so, so much,
キミだけに 伝えるよ
I'll tell it only to you.
走りなさい
Run,
早く もっと 早く
faster and faster,
悲しみに追いつかれないように
so that sadness does not overtake you.
探しなさい 明かりの灯る道を
Search for the path lit with light.
それは それは 眩しいでしょう
That must be, that must be dazzling.
挑みなさい 君の
Challenge those
美しさや 尊さを 傷つけるものに
who would harm your beauty and preciousness.
眠りなさい 疲れたのなら
Sleep, if you are tired,
眠りなさい
sleep,
神話を持たないあの 星座のように
like those constellations without a myth.
手を離したあと 君は気づくだろう
After letting go of my hand, you will realize
指の形 体温
the shape of my fingers, the warmth...
その名残りが胸を刺す
Their lingering trace pierces your heart.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget even the fact that you forgot,
悲しみも ぬくもりも 消えてしまえ
let both the sadness and warmth fade away.
されど今も 耳に残る歌
Yet even now, the song remaining in your ears,
高らかに咲いた 祝詞を唱うような
like chanting a high-blooming shinto prayer...
さよなら I do, I do Love you and you
Goodbye, I do, I do... Love you and you...
踊りなさい
Dance on,
誰に笑われようとも
no matter who laughs at you.
淡雪を払う
Brush off the light snow,
焔のように
like a burning flame.
叫びなさい
Shout out,
心から叫びなさい
shout from the bottom of your heart.
ここに確かに立ったと
Let it echo
響かせて
that you truly stood right here.
行き交うの空に
In the crossing sky,
遠花火が滲む
distant fireworks bleed.
帰るべき家を探す
Searching for a home to return to,
長い長い旅路を行くなら
if you're embarking on a long, long journey...
高らかに鳴らせ
Let it ring loud and clear;
その心臓は
that heart of yours
最後のひと打ちまで
until its very last beat
君のものだ
belongs to you.
涙 涙
Tears, tears,
あふれるかい
are they overflowing?
この孤独が
This loneliness,
君の周りを彩っているだろう
must be surrounding and coloring your world.
それは数百年の ホームシックでした
It was hundreds of years of homesickness.
無限さえも 数え終えて
Having finished counting even infinity,
怪物のような 世界の隅っこで
in the corner of a monster-like world,
戦い続ける人 君は
a person who keeps fighting—you are...
エルフ
Elf,
Elf.
旅は続く
The journey continues.
忘れたことも
Even the things you forgot,
忘れてしまえ
forget them all.
悲しみも ぬくもりも
The sadness, the warmth,
消えてしまえ
let them fade away.
今も 今も
Even now, even now,
君のことは
about you...
固く塞いだ
Tightly closed,
願うような
as if praying,
サヨナラ
goodbye...
I do, I do
Love you and you
IRIS OUT
ダメダメダメ
Stop, stop, stop,
脳みそ汁の中から
from inside my brain stem,
「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
morality screams "Quit it, you idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby, darling,
半端なくラブ！ときめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
insane love! A philosophy that has me giddy and sparking with anticipation.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
The way you look up at me is so adorable,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
it's almost illegal.
散らかす乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, before I know it, I've squandered it all.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
Born into this world, you are to blame.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
A ridiculously painful love sickness,
バラバラになる頭とこの身体
my head and this body fall to pieces.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
From my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out.
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
一体どうしよう この想いを
What on earth should I do with these feelings?
どうしよう あばらの奥を
What should I do? Deep inside my ribs,
ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
the rock sugar is melting, I feel like I'll throw up.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Pupils dilated to the max, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今 この世で 君だけ 大正解
Right now in this world, you alone are the absolute right answer!
ダーリン (ベイビー) ダーリン ダーリン (ベイビー) ダーリン...
Darling (baby) darling, darling (baby) darling...
ひっくり返っても勝ちようがない
Even if I flip things around, I can't win.
君だけルールは適用外
The rules don't apply to you alone.
四つともオセロは黒しかない
All four Othello discs are black,
カツアゲ放題
extortion at will.
君が笑顔で放った アバダケダブラ
You flung an "Avada Kedavra" with a smile,
デコに スティグマ 申し訳ねえな
a stigma on my forehead, my bad.
矢を刺して 貫いて
Pierce me with an arrow, run me through,
ここ弱点
right here at my weak spot.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
The way you look up at me is so adorable,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
it's almost illegal.
散らかす乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, before I know it, I've squandered it all.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
Born into this world, you are to blame.
パチモンでもいい 何でもいい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine,
今 君と名付いてる 全て欲しい
right now, everything named "you", I want it all.
頸動脈から アイラブユーが吹き出て
From my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out.
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
一体どうしよう この想いを
What on earth should I do with these feelings?
どうしよう あばらの奥を
What should I do? Deep inside my ribs,
ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
the rock sugar is melting, I feel like I'll throw up.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Pupils dilated to the max, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今 この世で 君だけ 大正解
Right now in this world, you alone are the absolute right answer!
世界...
The world...
Darling Darling Darling...
Darling, darling...
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show the answer,
無限に続く螺旋の先へ
to the spiral that continues endlessly.
夢幻
[Mugen]
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason that sounded like an excuse
儚い未来手繰った弱さ
is the weakness of clinging to a fleeting future.
それを強さとはき違えている
Mistaking that weakness for strength.
憎い 憎い
Hateful, hateful...
醜い 醜い
Ugly, ugly...
月を隠すほどの
Dark enough to hide the moon,
黒く 黒く
Black, black...
淀む心
A stagnant heart.
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでいる
Swaying, swaying...
花のように意思を繋ぐ
Connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away...
嵐のように心を裂く
Tearing hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show the answer,
無限に続く螺旋の先に 待つのは誰
Beyond the endless spiral, who is waiting?
生まれ落ちた宿命を飲んだ
Accepting the fate I was born into,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
I remembered the names of all those I bore.
爛れるほど心燃やす感情
Feelings that burn my heart to the point of decay.
憎い 憎い
Hateful, hateful...
醜い 醜い
Ugly, ugly...
世界を分かつほどの
Fierce enough to split the world,
怒り 怒り
Anger, anger...
燃やす心
A burning heart.
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでいる
Swaying, swaying...
花のように意思を繋ぐ
Connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away...
嵐のように心を裂く
Tearing hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show the answer,
無限に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral...
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞いよ
Listening to the wailing of demons, this is the end.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
Ending everything with all that dwells in this body.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人よ
Oh weak one, who entrusted your illusion to others...
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The brilliance of life over countless years,
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
In the setting sun illuminated by flickering prayers,
千夜を身に宿し
Bearing a thousand nights within myself,
解を押し付ける
Imposing my solution.
枯らしていく 枯らしていく
Withering away, withering away...
夢幻の夜に花を咲く
Making flowers bloom in the night of illusions.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Connecting, connecting...
嵐に種を撒いていく
Sowing seeds into the storm.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでいる
Swaying, swaying...
花のように意思を繋ぐ
Connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away...
嵐のように心を裂く
Tearing hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show the answer,
無限に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral...
待つのは誰
Who is waiting?
ということで、ニコに来ていただきました！
So, Nico has joined us here!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ニコたんデス！
Happy birthday! It's Nico-tan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よくお前歌いきれたな！
How on earth did you manage to finish singing that!
なんかもうね、顔が...顔はもう涙で滲んでいる...
I mean, your face... your face is all smudged with tears!
「だ、大丈夫か？」って
"Are you, are you okay?" she asks...
あはは！ありがとうございます！
Ahaha! Thank you so much!
いやいや、ありがとうございます！こちらこそ！
No, no, thank you! The pleasure is all mine!
ということで、2026年の生誕祭はですね
So, for this 2026 Birthday Live...
あの、ニコさんが出演ということで
...Niko-san is appearing as a guest,
あの、ニコさんもね、3Dになったということで
and since Niko-san also got a 3D model,
で、ニコさんが「いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って言ってくれてたんで
and Niko-san said, "I want to sing next to Lui-senpai someday,"
あはは！ありがとうございます！
Ahaha! Thank you!
なので、今日はお呼びさせていただきました！
That's why I invited her today!
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
いや、めちゃくちゃかっこいい曲を歌わせていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたか？
We got to sing such a super cool song, how did everyone enjoy it?
いやー...
Well...
ニコさん良かったねーって...
Everyone's like, "Good for you, Niko-san!"
いや、もうニコさんのことはいいんです！
Wait, never mind about me!
そんなことよりルイ先輩！ニコさんなんか...
More importantly, Lui-senpai!
今日は重大告知もあるし...
There's a major announcement today, and...
そうなんです！
That's right!
新衣装もあるんです！
There's also a new outfit!
出るんでしたっけ？
Is that coming out?
これね、たくさんね、こちらのハッシュタグ
Please use this hashtag a lot:
#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE ってありますんで
#TakaneLuiChouJuudaiSeitanLIVE
それでたくさんポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど
I'd be so happy if you could post a lot with it!
今日はたくさん告知もありますし
We have so many announcements today...
そうですよね！
That's true!
いや、重大告知の凄さも気になりますけど...
I mean, I'm curious about the huge announcement, but...
新衣装がやっぱり気になります！
I'm really curious about the new outfit!
ルイ先輩と言えば、ちょっとダークな感じなのかなとか...
When I think of Lui-senpai, I wonder if it'll be a bit dark...
黒っぽい感じなのかなーみたいな...
Or maybe something with dark/black colors...
あー、なるほどなるほど。そう思いますよね！
Ah, I see, I see. You'd think so, right?
ま、それもあります！
Well, there's that too!
それも！？
That too!?
はい！最初は固定投稿にも書かせていただいたんですけど
Yes! As I mentioned in my pinned post earlier...
新衣装は、最初はカラーバリエーションで...
The new outfit starts with color variations...
えぇ！？
What!?
ちょっと清純な感じの衣装になっております！
It's an outfit with a slightly pure and neat vibe!
え！？それもある...他にもあるってことですか？
Huh!? There's that... and even more variations?
はい！めちゃくちゃ大量にバリエーションを用意しておりますので
Yes! I've prepared a huge amount of variations, so...
なんかすごい騒いでる！
Wow, they're making a huge fuss in the background!
おかしいな...
That's strange...
うん、もういいや！今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Oh well! Thanks for coming today!
わかりました！私、楽屋で応援してます！
Understood! I'll be cheering for you from the dressing room!
それでは... あ、違います違います！そっち...
Well then... Ah, wait, wait! Not that way...
そっちは舞踏会会場なんで
That way leads to the ballroom!
駄目なんですか、ニコは？
Can't Niko go there?
ニコさんは呼んでない。招待状もらってないでしょ？
I didn't invite Niko-san. You didn't get an invitation, right?
もらってないけど...
I didn't, but...
じゃあ、すみませんが楽屋の方へあちらから...
Well then, sorry, but please head to the dressing room over there...
嫌だよー！
No way~!
はい、スタッフさんお願いします！
Yes, staff members, please escort her!
ルイ先輩、体調気をつけてください！
Lui-senpai, take care of your health!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
頑張ってください！
Good luck!
ありがとうねー！
Thanks a lot~!
ということで、ニコさんに行っていただきました！
And with that, Niko-san has departed!
はい！
Alright!
新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので
I'll be showing you lots of new outfits,
最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います！
so I hope you enjoy until the very end!
楽屋のニコさんも楽しんでくださいね！
Niko-san in the dressing room, enjoy it too!
それでは聴いてください！
Now then, please listen!
「ZIG-ZAG」
"ZIG-ZAG"
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー
One, two, three, four!
幸せって囁いた
Whispering "I'm happy,"
こびりついて離れない
It clings to me and won't let go.
有名無実の正義感が 思い出せないや
My nominal sense of justice can't recall it.
忘れたいから歌った
I sang because I wanted to forget.
恨むことも 憎むことも 賢くナイゆえできなかった
Unable to hold a grudge or hate, simply because I wasn't clever enough.
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your end,
笑ってしまいたい
I just want to laugh it off.
ホント ウソ ウソ ウソ
Truth, lies, lies, lies...
うそつき
Liar.
ヤダイヤダイヤダイヤダな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, no, no, I hate this! Hoping for a miracle just a little,
もうヤダイヤダイヤダイヤダ 価値観の違いね
Oh no, no, no, no! Differences in values, you know?
ギライギライギライギライな おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hate, hate, hate, hate! Gouging out every weird part,
薄氷の上で喧嘩
Fighting on thin ice,
好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma.
私 甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't become good at depending on others,
可愛げとかが足りなかった
Lacking cuteness and charm,
後悔か？
Is it regret?
うるさいよ！
Shut up!
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば きっといいことあるさとかそれくらい
"If you move past the past, good things will surely come," or something like that,
100も承知だ
I know that all too well!
願うことも 祈ることも 許されないから黒く染めた
Wishing and praying weren't allowed, so I dyed it black.
元の色も もう思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color anymore,
絡んだ運命の 糸 糸 糸 糸
The tangled thread, thread, thread, thread of fate!
ヤダイヤダイヤダイヤダな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, no, no, I hate this! Acting like the tragic heroine,
もうヤダイヤダイヤダイヤダ 諦めてしまえば
Oh no, no, no, no! If I just give up...
でもアイタイアイタイアイタイタイな 思考回路が破誕しちゃって
But I want, want, want to see you so badly, my mind is falling apart,
明日またきっと...
Tomorrow again, surely...
壊すけどいいの？
Is it okay if I break it?
トラウマにしたいのです
I want to make it a trauma for you...
です です で・で・で・で・です
I do, I do, I-I-I-I-do!
夢の中で君と手をつないでいるの
In my dream, I'm holding hands with you...
何も知らないあの頃のふたりのままで
...just as we were back then, knowing nothing.
でもわかっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I'll wake up soon...
それならいっそ君の手でそっと とどめを刺して
...so I'd rather you finish me off gently with your own hands.
それ 今 今 今
Right now, now, now!
痛い 痛い 痛いな
It hurts, hurts, it hurts so much!
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃっても
Even if I hope for a little miracle...
イエイイエイイエイイエイ 立ちが悪いわ
Yeah yeah yeah yeah, it's so nasty.
痛い 痛い 痛いな
It hurts, hurts, it hurts so much!
おかしいとこ全部えぐりとって
Gouge out everything that's wrong...
白状を結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
...and confess as much as you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です です で・で・で・で・です
I want to say goodbye to trauma! I do, I do, I-I-I-I-do!
世界欺く
Deceiving the world...
揺るぎない正義
...with unwavering justice,
ほどいて真実
unravel the truth...
転がっているの...
...into my hands.
大胆不敵な影が
A bold and fearless shadow...
華麗に踊る
...dances magnificently.
君が隠してる秘密
The secret you are hiding...
いつか聞かせてよ
...tell me about it someday.
伸ばした手で触れることは 誰もできない
No one can touch it with an outstretched hand.
君が隠してる世界
The world you are hiding...
僕に見させてよ
...show it to me.
揺れる難解な心
A complex, swaying heart,
解いて奪うその瞳
unravel it and steal those eyes.
不安がって泣いたって見つけらんないよ
You can't find it even if you cry in anxiety.
狙う真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the truth you aim for disappear?
たとえ世界欺く答えだとしても
Even if it's an answer that deceives the world,
「信じて」差し出す掌
reach out your palm and say, "Believe me."
決して逃げない怖くはないから
I will never run away, for I am not afraid.
目を開け弱さをかき消すんだ
Open your eyes and erase your weakness.
繰り替えされる運命に
To this repeating fate,
君は気づいてる？
are you aware of it?
僕が隠してる秘密
The secret I am hiding...
いつか聞かせるよ
...I will tell you someday.
歩み寄る偽りの影
An approaching shadow of falsehood,
君は知らない
you don't know about it.
芽生えた記憶は絡む
The sprouted memories intertwine...
必然の棘で
...with inevitable thorns.
守りたい思い出だけ
Just the memories I want to protect,
立ち向かって解くその絆
stand against it and untie those bonds.
何度だって助けるって
Saying I will save you no matter how many times,
揺らぎはしないよ
I will never waver.
隠す真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the hidden truth disappear?
たとえ世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if you turn the world into your enemy,
信じて僕だけ未来も
believe only in me, and the future too.
決して逃げない迷いはないから
I will never run away, for there is no hesitation.
シナリオ壊して抗うんだ
Destroy the scenario and fight back.
世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if the world turns against me,
信じて差し出す
Believe in me and reach out
手のひら
your palm.
決して離さない
I will never let go.
答えは届いた
The answer has reached us,
結んだ運命
the fate we bound
この手の中
is in these hands.
繰り返された答えだとしても
Even if it's an answer that repeats itself,
決して逃げない怖くはないから
I will never run away because there's nothing to fear,
抗うんだ
I will fight back.
何度も 何度も 走り続けるよ
Over and over, I'll keep on running!
Wake up 超新星
Wake up, supernova!
Shift up ギア回して
Shift up, turn the gears!
Speed up ハート倍転
Speed up, double your heart rate!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
Jump up 頂点へ
Jump up to the top!
Turn up 声合わせて
Turn up, raise your voices together!
Dreamer 未来繋いで
Dreamer, connect to the future!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
最高潮コンディション 闘志ガンガン尖っていこう
In peak condition, let fighting spirit shine sharp!
栄光のチャンピオン 淡々と狙っていこう
Steadily set our sights on the glory of being champion!
(ハイペースに) マイペース
(At a high pace) My pace!
(気合レースに) 超集中
(In a spirited race) Super focused!
駆けるセーブは限界 ハートに限界
Running with no saves, pushing our hearts to the limit!
U.M.A. Let's Go!
最高潮アンビション 研ぎ澄ませ勝負
Peak ambition, sharpen yourself for the showdown!
絶好のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでいこう
Let's grab this perfect chance with all our strength!
(ハイペースより) ハイペース
(Faster than a high pace) High pace!
(気合レースに) 猛進中
(In a spirited race) Charging forward!
賭ける覚悟をセット ぶっちぎっていくぞ
Set your determination, we're gonna tear right past them!
友と二人競い合った風の中でも
Even in the wind where I competed side by side with a friend,
大きな背中追いかけてた雨の中でも
even in the rain where I chased after that reliable back,
何百何千回と積み重ねてきた
hundreds and thousands of times we built this up,
だからどこまでも遠く
so let me go far, no matter where,
どこまでも高く
higher than anywhere,
誰よりも早く
faster than anyone,
誰よりも強く
stronger than anyone!
さあ、今！
Right now!
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
The feelings that broke into a run won't stop now!
誰にも渡せないゴールまで
Until the goal that I won't hand over to anyone,
弱気な気持ち蹴飛ばして 何度だってずっと
kicking away any weak feelings, again and again,
立ち上がって走り抜け
standing up and running through!
鳴り出した鼓動は収まらない
The pounding pulse won't quiet down!
最後まで全身全霊をかけて
Putting body and soul into it until the very end,
頂点 手を伸ばして
reach out a hand to the peak,
限界 超えていけ
break past your limits!
伝説を追い越して
Overtake legends!
勝利へ
Towards victory!
友と二人競い合ったあの喜びも
The joy of competing side by side with a friend,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
the admiration of chasing after that reliable back,
何千何万回生まれ変わっても
even if reborn thousands or tens of thousands of times,
何度も 何度も 走り続けるよ
over and over, I'll keep on running!
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
The feelings that broke into a run won't stop now!
誰しもが夢に見る未来まで
Until the future that everyone dreams of,
勇気も 傷ついても 迷いも 祈りも だってずっと
courage, hurt, hesitation, and prayers, always,
全てを繋いで行け
connect it all and keep going!
さあ、今！
Right now!
鳴り出した鼓動は収まらない
The pounding pulse won't quiet down!
最後まで全身全霊をかけて
Putting body and soul into it until the very end,
頂点 手を伸ばして
reach out a hand to the peak,
限界 超えていけ
break past your limits!
伝説を追い越して
Overtake legends!
勝利へ
Towards victory!
友と二人競い合ったあの喜びも
The joy of competing side by side with a friend,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
the admiration of chasing after that reliable back,
何千何万回生まれ変わっても
even if reborn thousands or tens of thousands of times,
何度も 何度も 走り続けるよ
over and over, I'll keep on running!
覚ませ本能を
Awaken your instinct,
起こせ感動を
spark the emotion,
刻め伝説を
carve out the legend,
叫べ Break out!!
shout out: Break out!!
Woah-oh-oh Break! Break! Break out!
離れていく足音 悔しくないのか？
Are you not frustrated as footsteps distance themselves?
錆びれていく舞台を前に 狼狽えるのか？
Will you panic before a stage falling into rust?
抗って切り開いて 見返す番だ
It's time to resist, cut your path, and show them all!
目を離すな 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
Don't look away, we're going to rewrite history!
だんだんだんだんだんだん上がっていく
Step by step by step it's getting higher,
歓声巻き起こすデッドヒート
a dead heat stirring up cheers!
だんだんだんだんだんだん迫っていく
Step by step by step it's drawing closer,
あと少し...せめぎ合う共鳴(シンパシー)
just a bit more... competing sympathy!
挑みたい Fight on!
Want to challenge! Fight on!
掴みたい Fight on!
Want to grab it! Fight on!
(Fight on!!) 掴みたい
(Fight on!!) I want to grab it
(Fight on!!) 刻みたい
(Fight on!!) I want to carve it
(Fight on!!) 伝えたい
(Fight on!!) I want to convey it
革命の火蓋切って
Strike the fuse of revolution
伝説の旗掲げてゆこう
Hoist the flag of legend and press on
さぁ legend-changer
Now, legend-changer
ロックに飛び込んで
Dive in with a rock spirit
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the ones who spark the frenzy
legend-changer
大胆に行こうぜ
Let's go boldly
本能醒ませ
Awaken your instinct,
感動起こせ
stir the thrill,
伝説刻んで
etch the legend,
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!!
stomp the earth, stomp, stomp, break!!
長い長い 夢の旅路を
Along the long, long journey of dreams,
一歩 また一歩と 確実に進んでいく
step by step, making steady progress.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に みんなの笑顔があると信じて
Believing that beyond where my sharp gaze fixes, everyone's smiles await,
さあ行け！
now, go!
鋭い眼差し
[Sharp Gaze]
無数の足跡にみる栄冠を
The glory traced in countless footprints,
憧れにして終わらせるな
don't let it end as mere admiration.
託された夢が堤を切って
The dreams entrusted to us burst through the dam,
今、私の闘志へと変わってゆく
and now, they turn into my fighting will.
さぁ legend-changer
Now, legend-changer
ロックに飛び込んで
Dive in with a rock spirit
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the ones who spark the frenzy
legend-changer
大胆に行こうぜ
Let's go boldly
本能醒ませ
Awaken your instinct,
感動起こせ
stir the thrill,
伝説刻んで
etch the legend,
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!!
stomp the earth, stomp, stomp, break!!
Wo-o-o Wo-o-o
Break break break out!!
もう救えない スクラップばかりのブルペンじゃ
There's no saving it in a bullpen full of scrap metal
ちゃちな青春も お涙も それすらナイもんな
Cheap youth and tearjerker moments—there's none of that either
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
Seriously unfunny—I can't even manage a single comedy scene
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わした さもそんな人生さ
Just mixing together cold chowder—that's pretty much this life
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを
This outfit with misaligned buttons,
いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
how long are we going to pretend not to notice?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Is that so? Well, there's no way to argue against it
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで
Accidentally running into a building on fire,
善かれと油を放り込んで
throwing in oil thinking it would help,
生活も 計画も
life and plans,
全部がpotatoになっていく
it's all turning into potato mash.
ぐつぐつ明日が泡吹いて
Tomorrow bubbles away, simmering,
白目のままに茹で上がって
boiling up with eyes rolled back,
将来像 成功法
future vision, recipe for success,
全部がpotatoになっていく
it's all turning into potato mash.
このままみんなで浸り散らかして
Let's all just wallow in this mess together,
どろどろに未来を溶かして
melting our future into a mush,
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living like this, let's get all crumpled up!
もう時間がない 我等に見下す権利などない
There's no more time; we have no right to look down on anyone
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
Even the boos shouted by the rabble are medals of honor now
相当に笑えない 誰だってそう言わざるを得ない
Seriously unfunny—anyone would be forced to agree
バカの１つ覚えのように 空回って ただバターになっている
Spinning our wheels endlessly like a fool, turning into pure butter
初めはこんなつもりじゃなかった
It wasn't supposed to be like this at first
誰か信じてくれやしないか
Won't someone please believe me?
一切、反証の余地はないが
Though there's absolutely no room for rebuttal
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で
Feigning total innocence,
ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
throwing firewood into the flames when the time is right,
生活も 計画も
life and plans,
全部がpotatoになっていく
it's all turning into potato mash.
こんがり明日が煮え切って
Tomorrow gets thoroughly cooked and browned,
姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
burning so brightly you can't even see it,
将来像 成功法
future vision, recipe for success,
全部がpotatoになっていく
it's all turning into potato mash.
このままみんなで浸り散らかして
Let me wallow in this mess together with everyone,
どろどろに未来を溶かして
melting our future into a mush,
そんなボウルの中で 憂さ晴らしだとしようぜ
inside that bowl, let me blow off some steam,
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living like this, let's get all crumpled up!
クイーンオブハート
[Title: Queen of Heart]
Welcome to the Wonderland
ここでは誰もが狂ってる
Everyone here is insane.
How are you doing, Miss?
But your time passes by the moonlight
どんなに叫んでも無駄
No matter how much you scream, it's useless,
死ぬまで帰れない
you can't go home until you die.
不気味な黒猫が
An eerie black cat
霧の中で笑う
laughs in the fog.
こんなにも濡れてるじゃないか
Look at you, you're so drenched.
官能の響く声にそっと耳を立てて
Gently strain your ears to the sensual voice,
まるでアリスのように
just like Alice.
殺さぬように
Neither killing you,
活かさぬように
nor letting you live,
壊れるまで愛してあげる
I'll love you until you break.
快楽は媚薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac.
どんな平和も焼け野のように
Any peace, like a burnt field,
刻みつくわ
will be carved into you.
Kiss me, be so insane
そう、これは夢の中
Yes, this is inside a dream,
童話の魔女が出てきて
a witch from a fairy tale appears,
告げる「バースデイでもないのにご馳走？」
saying "A feast, even though it's not your birthday?"
怪しい仮面も擦り寄りそうで
A suspicious mask seems to snuggle up to you.
ねぇ いつものままの貴方で
"Hey, just stay as you usually are,"
なんて気づかないフリ
pretending not to notice.
If I am dreaming...
Somebody wake me up
オフェリアさえ翻弄して
Even Ophelia is toyed with,
メリアンは走り出し
Merian starts running,
帽子屋がまた高らかに歌う
and the Mad Hatter sings loudly once again.
誰もが見ないフリで
When everyone pretends not to see
嘘を塗りつぶす時
and paints over the lies,
仮面の下の素顔が見える
the true face beneath the mask is revealed.
侵さぬように
Without violating,
穢さぬように
without defiling,
恥虐を咲かす花園
a garden where humiliation blooms.
狂い蜜が欲しいなら
If you want the mad nectar,
膝をつき地を舐め
get on your knees, lick the ground,
欲望を捧げて
and offer up your desires.
Yes, your Majesty
I give all my heart for you
殺さぬように
Neither killing,
活かさぬように
nor letting live,
この企てのディーラーさえ
so much that even the dealer of this plot
味わうほど
gets a taste of it...
私は
I am
The Queen of Heart
夢幻クライマックス
[Title: Mugen Climax]
さよなら 甘い街
Farewell, sweet city.
私
I am
遅れた人
a latecomer.
ねぇ 近づかないで
Hey, don't come near me.
理屈のない喜び
Irrational joy.
曖昧
Ambiguous,
未完成のあやまち 悟ったけど
I realized my incomplete mistakes, but...
それでは
And yet,
恋の季節
the season of love
きらめきは戻らない
and its sparkle will not return.
シナリオ通りのカルマ
A karma living according to the scenario...
飛び越えてきた人生
...a life spent jumping across.
望みがなくなって
Even if my wishes go away...
愛だけ残ったの
...only love will be left behind.
それぞれの幸せ振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our respective happinesses,
倒れないふたりで立っていようね
let's stand together as an unbreakable couple.
鮮やかでいてね
Stay vivid,
そのままでいてね
stay just the way you are.
消えない幻
An illusion that never disappears...
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Phantasmagorical climax, the last night.
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
Carve this endlessness innovatively.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい
Because even if you embrace me, I can't break...
強くなりすぎたから
...I've become far too strong.
あなたはわかんない
You don't understand...
おかえりからの孤独
...the loneliness after saying "I'm home".
それでも無神経に
Even so, insensitively...
季節が巡っていく
...the seasons continue to pass.
いつも褒めてくれた叱ってくれた
You always praised me, you always scolded me.
きっと楽になるし寂しくなるね
It'll be easier, but so lonely, won't it?
忘れないでいてね
Don't forget me.
憧れていてね
Keep longing for me.
朽ちない面影
An unfading memory...
だからディスティニー 時を越えて
That's why, destiny, passing through time,
同じ地球踏んでいられるわ
we can tread upon this same earth.
魂だけ側に置いてね
Keep just my soul at your side...
強く生きていけるの
...and I can live on strongly.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Phantasmagorical climax, the last night.
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
Carve this endlessness innovatively.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい
Because even if you embrace me, I can't break...
強くなりすぎた...
...I've become far too strong.
さみしい
"...I'm lonely."
だからディスティニー 時を越えて
That's why, destiny, passing through time,
同じ地球踏んでいられるわ
we can tread upon this same earth.
魂だけ側に置いてね
Keep just my soul at your side...
強く生きていこうね
...let's live on strongly together.
はいということで
Alright, so then!
ゲストパートを見ていただきましたがいかがだったでしょうか
How did you like the guest part that you just watched?
本当にね ゲストの人とこういうことやりたいっていうのを実現させていただきました
I was able to fulfill my wish to do something like this with the guests!
皆さん出演ありがとうございました
Everyone, thank you so much for appearing!
詳しくはいですね 明日の振り返り配信で いろいろ裏話だったりをお話しさせていただこうかなと思いますので
For details, I'll be talking about behind-the-scenes stories and more...
ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください
...during tomorrow's recap stream, so please come watch it!
そしていかがですか？新衣装いかがでしょうか？可愛いでしょう？
And how is it? What do you think of this new outfit? Isn't it cute?
たくさん差分があったんですけど気づきましたか？ま 気づきますよね
There were a lot of outfit variations, did you notice? Well, of course you did!
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして そしてウマ娘ワールドではですね 黒いパンツ姿であそこの階段から登場したんですけれども
At first it started with the white outfit, and then in the Umamusume section, I appeared from those stairs in black pants...
最初みんな「え、ルイどこ？」みたいな感じになってて面白かったんですけど
At first everyone was like "Wait, where's Lui?", which was funny...
ウマ娘を知ってる人は「まああそこから来るんやろうな」って腕組みしてたのが面白かったですね
People who know Umamusume were crossing their arms like "She's probably coming from there", which was hilarious!
この後ですね 21時20分からメン限で撮影会もございますので
After this, starting at 21:20, we'll have a photoshoot session on member-only stream...
そちらもぜひいろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので 撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます
...where I'd love to show off various variations too, so I'd be happy if you joined!
はい 重大発表はですね
Alright, as for the major announcement...
あと2曲あるんですけど 今から歌う曲の後で
...there are two songs left, and after the song I'm about to sing...
発表させていただきますので ぜひ皆さん心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います
...I will announce it, so please look forward to it!
じゃあ次の曲はですね 鷹嶺ルイ2ndアルバム『Lapis lazuli』から1曲歌わせていただきます
Now then, for the next song, I will perform a track from Takane Lui's 2nd album "Lapis lazuli".
『抗う君への鎮魂歌』です お願いします
"Requiem for You Who Resist". Please enjoy.
正しさだけ纏う術があれば
If only there were a way to wear only righteousness,
少しは救われるだろうか
would I be saved even a little?
その瞳へ問いかける
I question those eyes.
守るべきを 捨てるべきと 誰かに惑わされても
Even if misled into abandoning what should be protected,
心通わないなら
if our hearts cannot connect,
それは狂気だ
that is madness.
何も捨てずに...
Without discarding anything...
宛てなき力なき亡者...
an aimless, powerless ghost...
その覚悟なき思想に
In those uncommitted thoughts,
正しさなどない
there is no righteousness.
失えば失うほどにさらに気高く その意志で
The more I lose, the nobler I become with that will.
世界を怨め
Resent the world.
心がきしんで何度引き裂かれようと
Even if my heart groans and gets torn apart,
抗え
Fight back!
弱き一人を
To protect
守り抜くためのこの手のひらがどれだけ汚れてしまっても
this single weak soul, no matter how stained my hands become,
構わないさ
I don't care.
君が笑うなら
If it makes you smile,
僕は何にでもなる
I will become anything.
浅ましい期待 悦に浸るだけなら
If you merely wallow in self-satisfaction with shallow expectations,
人も獣も何一つ変わらない
humans and beasts are not one bit different.
鎖に似た自由を嘆いては
Lamenting a freedom that resembles chains,
歪に愛でるのでしょう
you cherish it in a distorted way.
どうか君だけは 僕を覚えていてほしい
Please, I want at least you to remember me.
放たれし君を 自由へと誘う
Guiding you, who have been unleashed, toward freedom.
俯けば俯くほどにさらに気高く その意志で
The more you hang your head, the nobler you become with that will.
世界を揺らせ
Shake the world.
心が歪んで何もかもが崩れても
Even if your heart warps and everything crumbles,
抗え
Fight back!
弱き一人を
To protect
守り抜くためのこの手のひらがどれだけ汚れてしまっても
this single weak soul, no matter how stained my hands become,
構わないさ
I don't care.
君が笑うなら
If it makes you smile,
壊してみせる
I will shatter it all.
心から君が笑えたとき
When you can smile from the bottom of your heart,
僕も報われるのだろう
I too will surely be rewarded.
不安も、否定も、葛藤も。
Anxiety, denial, and conflict too.
私に関歌で「反逆」する。
I will "rebel" through song.
1st Live 開催決定
[1st Live Confirmed]
REBELLION Takane Lui 1st Live
[REBELLION - Takane Lui 1st Live]
ここから始まる。私だけの物語。
It begins here. My own story.
はい、ということで！
Alright, so!
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！
My very first solo live concert has been confirmed!
ということで、
And so,
日程は半年後になるのですが、
the date will be half a year from now,
2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
on Wednesday, December 16, 2026!
会場は Kanadevia Hall です！
The venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末に holoX ライブがありまして
At the end of April, we have the holoX Live,
そして9月に NiePOX がありまして
then in September we have NiePOX,
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで
and in December, Takane Lui's solo live will take place!
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年なんじゃないですか、ルイ友さん？
2026 is going to be an insanely fun year for all of us, don't you think, Lui-tomo?
はい。ということでルイ友さんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんです けれど
Yes! I think I've talked about this with you all before,
私は前々からですね、今まで音楽活動で道を作ってきてくれた先輩、そら先輩だったり、すいちゃん、あずちゃん、そしてわため、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね
but for a long time, I've looked up to seniors like Sora-senpai, Sui-chan, AZ-chan, Watame, and Calli-senpai who paved the way in music...
ファーストライブから少しずつ段階、階段を上がっていって、広い会場でソロライブをするというそんな物語に憧れていました。
I've always admired the story of starting from a 1st live and slowly climbing the stairs step by step to perform a solo live in a huge venue.
だからもし私がライブをやることになった際には、ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォース
So if I ever got the chance to hold a live, I wanted it to be 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th...
順々に会場を大きくして、ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい
gradually expanding the venue size, to eventually fulfill my dream of performing in an arena.
はい、そう思っていて、ルイ友さんにはね、常々お伝えをしていたと思います。
Yes, that's what I thought, and I think I've mentioned that to you Lui-tomo all along.
そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動を頑張りたいなと思って、今まで努力をしてきました。そしてこれからもします！
That's why I wanted to work hard to reach a point where I could hold regular solo lives, and I've been striving for that until now. And I will keep striving!
最近のホロライブはですね、結構より多くの方が 入る会場での開催が多くて、私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは思っていたんですけれども
Lately, Hololive events have been held in venues capable of holding much larger crowds, so I thought my dream might be difficult to achieve...
こうやって私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えるべく、まずは私の希望だった Kanadevia Hall にてファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！おめでとう！ありがとう！
However, everyone understood my dream and helped make it come true, allowing me to hold my 1st live at Kanadevia Hall, which was my initial hope! Congratulations and thank you!
そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます！ありがとうございます。
And thank you so much for getting it trending as well! Thank you so much!
ここからが鷹嶺ルイの新章の、新章の物語の始まりでございます。
From here on out marks the beginning of a new chapter in Takane Lui's story.
まずはファーストライブを開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれども
I know I should probably focus on holding the 1st live before thinking about what's next,
私はセカンド、サード、フォース、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております。
but I already have a vision for the 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and lives beyond that.
今回、生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように Luminous Stairs、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために
Just like the title of this birthday live implies, "Luminous Stairs," in order to run up those glowing stairs...
そして一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために
and to continue weaving this story together with you all...
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は、次に繋げるために応募したりライブを見てくれると嬉しいです！
If you feel even a little bit like coming, I'd be so happy if you apply or watch the stream to help carry us into the next step!
ライブのタイトルは「Rebellion」になっております！
The title of the live is "Rebellion"!
はい、「Rebellion」です。
Yes, "Rebellion."
「反逆」という意味でございます。私がいつも抱えてる不安や、そして色々な否定の声
It means "to rebel." The anxieties I constantly hold, the various voices of doubt...
そして私自身の葛藤、これからも私はそれを私の歌で反逆していきたい、そんな気持ちを込めさせていただきました。
and my own inner struggles—I want to rebel against all of it through my songs. I poured those feelings into this title.
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください！
I'm preparing a lot to make it the best live possible, so please look forward to it!
はい！ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、アーティスト写真を作りました！こちらです！
Alright! Since a brand new story for Takane Lui is starting, we created a new artist photo! Here it is!
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね！カッコ可愛い！
Yes, it looks super cool, right? Cool and cute!
アーティスト活動の際にはこちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いします！
I plan to use this visual for my music artist activities, so please keep an eye out for it!
そしてここまですでにファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが
And up until now, I've released 1st, 2nd, acoustic, and full albums,
今回、ライブを盛り上げるために4曲
and this time, to hype up the live performance...
新しく作りまして、収録させていただいたミニアルバムも本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です！
we created 4 new songs! Pre-orders for this mini-album start today right after this stream ends!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ(笑)
Takane Lui sure has a lot of songs now, huh? (laughs)
はい、『LEGENDARY』というタイトルをつけさせていただきましたミニアルバムでございます。
Yes, this mini-album is titled "LEGENDARY".
この後に披露する新曲も入っております。
It includes the new song I'll be performing right after this!
完全生産限定盤には全員にサインがつきます！
The Limited First Edition will come with signatures for everyone!
完全生産限定盤には全員に直筆サインがつきますので、日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください！
Every copy of the Limited First Edition will feature a handwritten signature, as my way of showing daily gratitude, so please pre-order it!
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはサインついてないんですけど、通常盤もございますのでぜひお手元に取っていただけますと嬉しいです。
There is also an affordable Standard Edition. This one doesn't include a signature, but I'd be happy if you pick up a copy!
今回のライブ、そしてこの後に予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、#鷹嶺ルイの反逆 となっております！
The hashtag for both this live and the mini-album available for pre-order after this stream will be #鷹嶺ルイの反逆 (#TakaneLuiRebellion)!
はい、皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね！ビジュアル良いでしょ？ビジュアル良いよね！
Please post a lot and hype it up, okay? The key visual looks great, right? It really does!
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした！まだお知らせはございます！
That's all for the announcements regarding the solo live and mini-album! But wait, there's more!
はい、お知らせと重大告知がございます。次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！
There is another major announcement. Up next is the long-awaited merch reveal!
はい、こちら！「鷹嶺ルイ 誕生日記念 2026」ということで...
Yes, right here! "Takane Lui Birthday Celebration 2026"!
キービジュアルはですね、
The key visual is...
今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て、ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです。
Takane Lui wearing the new outfit unveiled today, eating cake.
久乃のらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました。可愛いでしょ？
Illustrated by Kuno Norari-sensei. Isn't it cute?
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at each item!
1つ目はこちら、アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております。
First up is this: the Acrylic Diorama Stand.
キービジュアルを使用したアクリルジオラマになっております。
It's an acrylic diorama featuring the key visual.
ルイ友さんとですね、がんもも可愛く執事風におめかしをしてます。可愛い！
Lui-tomo and Ganmo are also cutely dressed up like butler/maid! Cute!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
新衣装のこちらとかについている、2種類のエンブレムをモチーフにしたピンバッジでございます！
A set of pin badges based on the two emblems on my new outfit!
いろんなところにつけて密かにルイ友アピールをしてください。おしゃれでしょ？
Attach them to various places to subtly show you're a Lui-tomo. Stylish, right?
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます。おしゃれ！
It's a pouch inspired by the new outfit. Stylish!
裏面はですね、メッシュポケットになっているので、
The back side has a mesh pocket,
缶バッジはもちろん、今回一緒に販売するピンバッジもつけやすいデザインになっております！
so it's designed to easily attach tin badges and the pin badges sold today!
最後はー、これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら！
Lastly, you probably wanted this, right? This!
新衣装のショートパンツバージョンのホロフレと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです！可愛い！
A plushie of the short pants version of the new outfit, about HoloFriends size! Cute!
ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
I'd be happy if you could take this opportunity to welcome it home. Thank you!
フルセット購入特典はこちら！
The full set purchase bonus is this!
ポストカードになっておりまして、数量限定版と通常版がございます。
It's a postcard, available in limited and regular editions.
数量限定版は直筆サインがつきます！たくさん用意しておるので、ゆっくり選んでください！
The limited edition comes with a handwritten autograph! Take your time choosing!
販売時間はですね、少し余裕を持たせて21時15分からカートオープンです！
As for sales timing, giving a bit of extra time, the cart opens at 21:15!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That was the merch introduction!
そしてもう1つ、重大告知です！こちら！
And one more thing, an important announcement! This!
なんと！私が夢見ていました、BAYFM78にてレギュラー番組決定しましたー！
Guess what! My dream of a regular radio program on BAYFM78 is official!
放送日はですね、毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分、初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっております！
It airs every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57, starting Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用のお便りを募集するので、メールアドレスも公開しますので、Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします！楽しみにしててねー！
We'll accept messages for episode 1 on X and post the email address, so follow us!
はい！次の曲が最後の曲になります。
Alright! The next song will be the last song.
先ほども紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして、名前は「Soar」と言います！
It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled "Soar"!
ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って、みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきました！
Wanting to sing together at the solo live, I made a new song where everyone can cheer!
ナナホシさんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております。
It's a refreshing song written for me by Nanahoshi-san.
このあと21時から、ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります！
After this from 21:00, there will also be a Music Video premiere!
楽曲は本日24時にリリースです！
The track releases at 24:00 today!
この曲はですね、コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております！
For this song, the chorus is sung by Holo members!
ライブまでにたくさん聞いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot and learn it before the concert!
では早速聴いていただきましょう！
So without further ado, please listen to it!
皆さんと一緒に歌いたい曲、「Soar」です。どうぞ！
The song I want to sing with everyone, "Soar". Here you go!
何度でも君を呼んで　また歩いてゆく
No matter how many times, I call out to you and keep walking on
一歩　踏み出したらもう未来さ
Take one step forward and it's already the future
昨日つまずいた道も　今日からは近道だ
Even the path I stumbled on yesterday becomes a shortcut from today
息をするたびに広がる景色
The scenery that expands every time I breathe
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me it's okay to believe in myself
つぶやきも希望になって
Even a whisper turns into hope
あふれては声になって
Overflowing and turning into a voice
何度目を閉じても消せないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it
高く飛べるよ　そうだろう　抑えられない
I can fly high, right? I can't hold it back
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives permission for my reason to spread my wings
もう決めたよ　迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate
向かい風も　きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is surely proof that I'm moving forward
君に伝えるんだ
I will convey it to you
どんな重力も心までは
No gravity can reach my heart to
縛れない　曲げられない
Bind it or bend it
この手で確かめたい
I want to make sure with these hands
胸焦がした思いで
With my heart burning with passion
爪痕をさぁ刻んで
Come on, engrave your mark
嵐の空模様切り裂いて
Tear through the stormy sky
もっと輝くよ そうだろう
I'll shine even brighter, right?
叫べばいい
All you have to do is shout.
憧れより眩しい唄 そして激しい唄
A song more dazzling than longing, and a fierce song.
いつか耳を塞いだ
Those hands that once covered my ears...
その両手が きっと翼になる
...will surely turn into wings.
そう思うんだ
That's what I believe.
ゆずれない衝動
An unyielding impulse.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
I can fly high, right?
抑えられない
I can't hold it back.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives permission for my wings to spread,
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is proof that I'm moving forward.
君に伝えるんだ
I'm going to convey it to you.
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
No matter how many times, I'll call your name and keep walking on.
皆さん本日は生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday stream today!
ソロライブ楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to the solo live!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ルイ友へ みんなの応援のおかげで… ついに私もソロライブできるよ…！！ 本当にありがとう♡ もっともっと輝いて光り輝く階段をのぼって、 いろんな景色をみせてあげるね (任せろー！！) 私の物語には君が必要です！！ これからもよろしくね！！
[On-screen Message] To Lui-tomo, Thanks to everyone's support... I can finally hold a solo live...!! Thank you so much ♡ I'll shine brighter and brighter, climbing the glowing stairs, and show you all kinds of sights! (Leave it to me!!) You are essential to my story!! Please keep supporting me!!